1991 年 6 月 26 日
On June the 26th, 1991,
在华盛顿特区 马里兰州和西弗吉尼亚州的大部分地区
Washington DC, much of Maryland and West Virginia,
我祖国的许多地区都因公共电话网络的大规模故障而瘫痪了
major portions of my home state were paralyzed by massive failure in the public telephone network.
然而 随着技术变得越来越复杂 网络系统越来越相互依存
And yet, as technology becomes more sophisticated and network systems more interdependent,
反复发生故障的可能性也会增加
the likelihood of recurrent failures increases.
这种状况的发生 是之前就警告过的
It's not as though there wasn't warning that this would happen.
在 20 世纪 90 年代初
In the early 1990s,
有 1200 万美国人遭受了大规模的电话网络故障
12 million Americans were hit with massive phone network failures.
人们不能给医院打电话
People couldn't call the hospital.
企业不能给客户打电话
Businesses couldn't call customers.
父母不能打电话给托儿所
Parents couldn't call their daycares.
对于一个基础设施严重依赖于万物互联的计算机系统的国家来说
It was chaos and it was also a serious wake-up call,
a wake-up call for a country whose infrastructure relied heavily
这是一场混乱 也是一声警钟
on the computer systems that networked everything.
这些计算机网络变得越来越大
Those computer networks were growing larger and larger,
然后当它们出现故障时
and then when they failed,
故障的后果就会极为严重
yeah, they failed big time.
电脑故障会导致电话系统崩溃
A computer failure caused that phone system crash.
在今天 代码中的一行小错误的后果比以往时候都要严重
This tiny one line bug in the code, and today the consequences of little bugs like that are higher than ever.
我是 Saron Yitbarek
I'm Saron Yitbarek
这里是是红帽公司的原创播客节目《代码英雄》
and this is Command Line Heroes, an original podcast from Red Hat.
因此 软件安全性和可靠性比以往任何时候都重要
So software security and reliability matter more than ever.
传统的瀑布式开发方法中 安全性只是一个附加流程而已
The old waterfall approach to development, where security was just tacked onto the end of things,
这样的方式已经不再适用
that doesn't cut it anymore.
我们生活在一个 DevOps 的世界里
We're living in a DevOps world
一切都变得更快、更敏捷、扩展性更强
where everything is faster, more agile, and scalable
这在电话网络崩溃时是人们无法想象的
in ways they couldn't even imagine back when that phone network crashed.
这意味着我们的安全和可靠性标准必须不断改进 以应对这些挑战
That means our security and reliability standards have to evolve to meet those challenges.
在本集中 我们将研究如何将安全工作集成到 DevOps 中
In this episode, we're going to figure out how to integrate security into DevOps,
我们还将探索提升运营可靠性和弹性的新方法
and we're also exploring new approaches to building reliability and resilience into operations.
在介绍了所有这些之后 我们还有很多东西可以讨论
Even after covering all that, we know there's so much more we could talk about
因为在 DevSecOps 的世界里
because in a DevSecOps world,
不管对于开发人员 还是运营人员 现状都在快速变化
things are changing fast for both the developers and operations.
从不同的立场上来看 这些变化的意义也随之改变
These changes mean different things depending on where you're standing,
但这是我们的看法
but this is our take.
我们也很想听到你们的观点
We'd love to hear yours too -
如果你认为我们错过了什么 不要害羞 - 在网上联系我们
so don't be shy if you think we've missed something - hit us up online.
好了 让我们开始探索这个全新的领域吧
All right, let's dig in and start exploring this brand new territory.
事情就是这样 想让安全性和可靠性跟上时代的步伐
Here's the thing, getting security and reliability up to speed,
并为 DevOps 世界做好准备
getting it ready for a DevOps world,
我们就必须对工作方式进行一些关键的调整
means we have to make a couple of key adjustments to the way we work.
第一 我们必须拥抱自动化
Number one, we have to embrace automation.
我是说 想想如果要人为实行两步验证 对后勤的负担会多么庞大
I mean, think about the logistics of say two-factor authentication.
想想那些难以想象的艰巨任务吧
Think of the impossibly huge task that poses.
很显然 你不能仅仅通过增加员工来解决问题
It's pretty obvious you're not going to solve things by just adding more staff,
所以第一点就是拥抱自动化
so that's number one, embracing automation.
然后 第二点 这个可能不是那么明显
And then, number two, and this one's maybe less obvious,
那就是真正地去改变文化 使安全从业者不再受人回避
it's really changing the culture so security isn't a boogeyman anymore.
稍后我将解释我所说的改变文化的含义
I'm going to explain what I mean by changing the culture later on,
但是 让我们分别解释这两点
but let's tackle these two steps one at a time.
首先 拥抱自动化
First up, embracing automation.
以前 应用程序的部署在每次发布之前 都需要人为的安全审查
Once upon a time app deployment involved a human-driven security review before every single release,
而你多半也注意到了 - 人为审查可能会有亿点慢
and I don't know if you've noticed, but humans, they can be a little slow.
因此 如果要将安全工作整合进 DevOps
That's why automation is such a key part
自动化必然是其中不可或缺的一环
of building security into DevOps.
以 Verizon 最近的数据泄露报告为例
Take, for example, this recent data breach report from Verizon.
他们发现 81% 的黑客入侵涉及密码被盗或者弱密码
They found that 81% of all hacking–related breaches involve stolen or weak passwords,
从表面上看 这是一个非常简单的问题
and that's on the face of it such a simple problem.
但问题的规模却很大
But it's a simple problem at a huge scale.
就像我之前说的
Like I mentioned before,
你不能靠增加人手解决 3000 万个密码问题 对吧？
you're not going to staff your way out of 30 million password issues, right?
问题在于解决大规模问题
The hurdle is addressing that problem of scale, the huge size of it,
而每次的答案都是一样的 那就是自动化 自动化
and the answer is the same every time. It's automation, automation.
如果你总等着人参与进来 那么服务的规模就不会扩大
If you wait for a human being to get involved, it's not going to scale.
Vincent Danen 是红帽公司产品安全部门的主管
Vincent Danen is the director of product security at Red Hat
在过去的 20 年里 他见证了 DevOps 的快速发展
and over the 20 years he's been at this, he's watched as DevOps created a faster and faster environment.
安全团队不得不努力追赶
Security teams have had to race to keep up.
刚开始的时候 每个月都有漏洞
When I started, it was a vulnerability per month
后来变成了隔周一次 然后是每周都有
and then it started becoming every other week and then every week,
现在 每天都能找到几百个漏洞
and now we're into the, you know, literally finding hundreds of these things every day.
有趣的是 正如 Vincent 所说
What's interesting here is that Vincent says
随着安全团队的进步 漏洞会越来越多 而不是越来越少
there are actually more vulnerabilities showing up as security teams evolve, not less.
我们永远不会说 哦 我们现在安全了 我们做完了 我们的工作结束了
We'll never get to the point where we say, oh, we're secure now, we're done. Our job is over.
安全工作会一直存在 就像呼吸一样 这是必须要有的
It'll always be there. It's just something that has to be as normal as breathing now.
事实证明 对于安全性和可靠性团队来说 细节的问题变得越来越重要
It turns out what counts as an issue for security and reliability teams is becoming more and more nuanced.
只要我们还在寻找这些漏洞 我们就会发现更多
As we're looking for these things, we're finding more
而且这个趋势还将继续 因为你会发现新的漏洞类型
and this trend is going to continue as you find new classes of vulnerabilities
以及以前不受重视的因素
and things we maybe didn't think were important or
甚至是在此前未知的因素
didn't even know they existed before.
我们发现漏洞的速度更快了 它们的数量也变得更多
We're finding out about these things much faster and there's more of them.
因此工作的规模爆炸性增长
And so the scale kind of explodes.
新知识、软件的体量、消费者的数量
It's knowledge. It's volume of software. It's number of consumers.
都促进了安全领域的进步以及漏洞的增加
All of these things contribute to the growth of security in this area and the vulnerabilities that we're finding.
一旦你将安全视为一个不断发展的问题
Once you see security as an evolving issue
而不是随着时间的推移而 “得到解决”的问题
rather than one that gets "solved" over time,
那么自动化的理由就会变得更加充分
the case for automation, well, it gets even stronger.
嗯 我认为有了自动化
Well, I think with automation
你可以很快将新的流程集成到你的开发流水线中
you can integrate this stuff into your development pipelines in a way that is very fast, for one.
其二 你不需要人类来做这些工作 对吧？
For two, you don't require human beings to do this effort, right?
计算机不需要睡觉
Computers don't need to sleep,
所以你可以在处理器允许的情况下以最快速度审查代码
so you can churn through code as fast as your processors will allow
而不是人为查看某些可能相当冗长乏味的内容
rather than waiting for a human to pour through some maybe rather tedious lines of code
来查找漏洞
to go looking for vulnerabilities.
通过模式匹配和启发式方法
And then with pattern-matching and heuristics,
在开始编写代码的时候 你就可以知道代码中那些地方是易受攻击的
you can actually determine what's vulnerable even at the time of writing the code to begin with.
如果在你编写代码的时候
So if you have, like, a plug-in, you know,
在你的 IDE 或者工具中有一个插件
for your IDE or your tool that you're using to write your code,
它能告诉你 嘿 这看起来有点可疑
it can tell you as you're writing it, like, hey, maybe this looks a little fishy,
或者你刚刚引入了一个漏洞
or you've just introduced a vulnerability
在你提交代码之前你都可以纠正这些疑点或者漏洞
and you can correct these things before you even commit the code.
写代码时就能做安全检查 这是一大红利
Security on the move. That's a huge bonus.
每一天 甚至每一小时 都会有新的开发任务被完成
There's just so much that's coming out every, every day, every hour even.
通过持续集成和持续部署
With continuous integration and continuous delivery,
你写了代码 10 分钟后它就被部署了
you write code and it's deployed 10 minutes later.
因此 在代码被推送之前自动进行验证是很有必要的
so it's really critical to get that validation of that code automatically prior to it being pushed out.
我们可以使用各种各样的工具来完成这个任务
A whole breadth of tools are available so we can actually get this done,
不管是静态代码分析 还是 IDE 的插件 或者别的什么选项
whether it's static code analysis or plug-ins for your IDE or a whole bunch of other options.
我们将在 redhat.com/commandlineheroes 上
We'll share some of our favorites in the show notes for this episode
分享一些我们最喜欢的工具
over at redhat.com/commandlineheroes.
一旦我们有了这些工具 它们将帮助我们把安全放在首位
Once we've got those tools in place, they help keep security top of mind.
结果就是 DevOps 被重新定义为 DevSecOps
The result, DevOps gets re-imagined as DevSecOps.
安全被纳入到流程中
Security gets baked into the process.
就像开发人员和运维人员结合的方式一样
In the same way that developers and operations kind of combined,
你将这两个领域合成到了一个领域
you took those two disciplines to generate one.
现在 你有了 DevOps
Now you have DevOps,
并将安全这第三个组件与开发和运维集成到一起
and taking that third component of security and integrating that in with development and operations,
我认为这非常重要
I think is really important because
如果出事后才考虑安全性 安全工作会变得极为被动 极为昂贵
having security as the afterthought is what makes security so reactive, so expensive,
也可能损害消费者的利益
so damaging or potentially damaging to consumers.
如果你一开始就把安全代入其中
And when you plug that in right at the beginning,
完成开发任务之后 从头到尾进行安全检查 背后就是运维的工作
you have development being done, securities in there from start to finish and the operations work.
当然 就像我们在这一集的开头提到的
Of course, like we mentioned at the top of the episode,
自动化只是图景的一半 而 Vincent 也明白这一点
automation is really just one half of a bigger pie and Vincent gets that.
自动化之外还有其他部分
It's not just one piece.
不能仅仅在你的 CI/CD 流水线中随便引入一个工具就期望一切都变好
You can't just, you know, throw a tool in your CI/CD pipeline and expect everything to be okay.
CI/CD：指“持续集成、持续交付、持续部署”
是一种工业化的软件开发流程 通过大量的自动化 让服务能被快速更改、快速上线
为了达到我们希望看到的最终有益结果
There's a whole gamut of different techniques and technologies and behaviors
需要使用各种技术和行为
that are required to produce those ultimate beneficial results that we want to see.
自动化确实让我们做到了一半
Automation does get us partway there,
但我们必须记住另一部分 - 稍微模糊一点的那一部分
but we've got to remember the other piece - that slightly fuzzier piece.
跟我一起说：那就是文化部分
Say it with me, the culture piece,
让开发者和运维人员都一起参与进来
getting developers and ops both on board
这样这些问题就不再是可怕的问题
so that these issues aren't boogeyman anymore.
我们必须改变文化
We have to change a culture
而有些人正在以一种最不痛苦的方式来做到这一点：
and some folks are learning to do that in the least painful way possible,
通过游戏
with games.
现在让我们来看看运维的那一面
Let's take a swing over to the op side of things now.
如今建立庞大的基础设施很容易
It's so easy to stand up huge infrastructure these days,
但这并不意味着我们应该做粗制滥造的工作
but that doesn't mean we should be doing shoddy work.
我们仍然应该努力改进我们的系统 确保可靠性
We should still be hammering on our systems, ensuring reliability,
未雨绸缪
figuring out how to prepare for the unexpected.
这就是 Jesse Robbins 正在努力实现的
That's the mindset Jesse Robbins is working to bring about.
如今 Jesse 是 Orion Labs 的 CEO
Today Jesse is the CEO of Orion Labs,
但在此之前 他在亚马逊是著名的“灾难大师”
but before that he was known as the master of disaster over at Amazon.
在那里 Jesse 发挥他的才智
During his time there, Jesse was pretty much a wizard
让大家对问题至少有了了解
at getting everybody at least aware of these issues.
他通过一个叫做 “游戏日” 的活动来做到这一点
And he did it with something called Game Day.
这些活动有时会让成千上万的员工参与故障演练
These can involve thousands of employees running through disaster scenario drills,
通过灾难演练来习惯系统失灵的状况
getting used to the idea of things breaking
并了解其发生的原因和方式
and getting intimate with the why and the how.
下面是 Jesse 和我的讨论
Here's Jesse and me talking it over,
话题是提升运营可靠性和弹性的方式
looking especially at how reliability and resilience get built into the operation side.
大家都知道你做了很多非常酷的事情
Okay, so you are known for many things, and one of those things is
其中之一就是你在亚马逊做的活动 - “游戏日”
the exercise "Game Day",
那是什么?
what you did at Amazon. What is that, what's Game Day?
Yeah
那是什么?
what you did at Amazon. What is that, what's Game Day?
“游戏日” 是我创建的一个项目
So Game Day was a program that I created
它通过大规模破坏来测试最脆弱系统的运行情况
to test the operational readiness of the most vulnerable systems
by breaking things at massive scale.
如果你是 Netflix 的 “混沌猴子” 的粉丝
So if you're a fan of what's called Chaos Monkey Now by the Netflix people and others,
“游戏日” 则是我创造的这一项目的后继者
Game Day was the name for my program that definitely proceeded all of that.
实际上 它非常专注于建立一种卓越的运营文化
It was really heavily focused on building a culture of operational excellence,
建立大规模测试系统的能力
building the capability to test systems at massive scale when they're breaking,
当系统崩溃时 能了解它们是如何崩溃的以改进它们
learn how they break to improve them.
然后还要建立一种文化
And then also to build a culture
能够对事件做出反应并恢复
that is capable of responding to and recovering from incidents in situations.
它是按照事故指挥系统来设计的
And it was all modeled and is all modeled
after the incident command system,
这是世界各地的消防部门用来处理各种规模事故的系统
which is what the fire departments use around the world for dealing with incidents of any size.
它的诞生源于…
It was sort of born from ...
Jesse 早在 2005 年就经过训练成为一名消防员
Crazy side note, Jesse trained to be a firefighter back in 2005.
在那儿 他了解了这个事故指挥系统
And that's where he learned this incident command system
最终激发了 “游戏日” 的灵感
that ended up inspiring Game Day.
因此 所有做这些故障演练的开发人员
So all the developers doing these disaster scenarios out there,
都要感谢 Jesse 对消防和应急管理的激情
you've got Jesse's passion for firefighting and emergency management to thank for that.
好了 回到我们的谈话
Okay, back to our chat.
评估系统弹性时 应着眼于其整体的图景
Resilience is the ability of a system,
系统中包括人员 以及这些人为应对变化而作的准备
and that includes people and the things that those people build to adapt to change,
弹性是系统整体应对失败和干扰的能力
to respond to failures and disturbances.
而建立这种弹性的最佳方法之一
And one of the best ways to build that
即 建立一种文化 使人们能够对逆境做出反应
to build a culture that can respond to those types of environments
并真正理解这些环境如何运作的方法
and really understands how those work
就是提供人员培训演习
is to provide people training exercises.
这些演习可以很简单
And those exercises can be as simple as something like,
比如重启服务器
you know, rebooting a server
也可以很复杂 比如关闭整个数据中心
or as complicated as a injecting massive scale faults
以此造成大规模故障等等
by turning off entire datacenters
以及在两者之间的各种可能性
and kind of everything in between.
所以 “游戏日” 首先是一个过程
And so what a Game Day is is first of all a process
在这个过程中 你通过让整个组织聚集在一起
where you prepare for something by getting an entire organization together
讨论系统如何发生故障
and kind of talking about how systems fail
并思考人类对故障发生的预期
and thinking about what human beings know about how they expect failure to happen.
而这个演习本身
And that exercise by itself
常常是 “游戏日” 开始时最有价值的部分之一
is often one of the most valuable parts of kind of the beginning of a Game Day.
但是 当你实际对系统做了破坏后
But then you actually run an exercise where you break something.
这种破坏可大可小
It could be something big, it could be something small.
也有可能经常发生
It could be something that breaks all the time.
当你这样做的时候
And when you do that,
你就可以看到每个人是如何反应的
you're able to study how everyone responds where things can move to.
你看到系统崩溃了
You can see the system breaking
可能是崩溃了也没关系的组件
and that might be something that is safe to break,
可能是一个被充分理解的组件
a well-understood component
也可能这次崩溃暴露了一个潜在的缺陷
or it might be something that exposes what we call a latent defect.
这些问题隐藏在软件、技术或者大规模的系统中
Those are those problems hiding in software or in technology or in a system at scale
只有当你遇到极端或者意外事件时
that we only can find out about
我们才能发现
when you have an extreme or an unexpected event.
“游戏日” 的目的是为了训练员工并且建立系统
It's really designed to train people and to build systems that
并让你了解它们如何在压力下工作
you understand how they're going to work under stress and under strain.
所以当我听到 “游戏日” 的时候 我就会想
And so when I hear Game Day, it makes me think,
“这是对某个特定事件的回应吗?
“Was this a response to something very specific that happened, that inspired it?
它是从哪儿来的?”
Where'd it come from?”
“游戏日” 刚开始的一段时间内
So Game Day started during a period of time
因为我知道自己的角色
where I knew because of my role and because of my unique background
以及作为消防员和应急管理人员的背景
as a firefighter and emergency manager,
因此 我知道
that it was important to change the cultural approach
将文化从注重预防失败的观念转变为拥抱失败非常重要
from focusing on the idea of preventing failure to instead embracing failure,
接受失败发生
accepting that failure happens.
促使我这样做的部分原因是我自己的经历
And part of what inspired that was both my own experience,
你知道 了解系统
you know, understanding systems,
比如建筑是如何倒塌的 市政基础设施是如何崩溃的
how like buildings fail and how civic infrastructure fails,
以及灾难是如何发生的
and how disasters happened,
以及灾难给人们的压力
and the strain that that puts on people.
如果环顾我所在工作场所的复杂性和运营规模
And saying, well, if we look at the complexity and operational scale
that we have at the place of employment that I was at,
就会知道 如果想要真的打造出
the only way that we're really going to build and change
一个高可靠性、持续在线的环境
and become a high-reliability, always-on environment,
唯一的办法就是采用消防服务的模式
is truly to embrace the fire service approach.
我们知道失败会发生
Where we know that failures will happen.
不存在灾害是否发生的问题 只存在时间问题
It's not a question of if, it's a question of when.
就像我之前的消防队长说的
And then as my old fire chief would say,
不是你选择时机 而是时机选择你
you don't choose the moment, the moment chooses you.
你能做的唯一选择就是 在它发生前尽量做足准备
You only choose how prepared you are when it does.
哦 这句话不错
Oh, that's a good one.
所以当你第一次开始举行 “游戏日”
So when you first started doing the Game Days
并思考如何为灾难场景做准备时
and thinking about how to be prepared for disaster scenarios,
每个人都同意了吗？你得到任何反对意见了吗？
was everyone on board with this or did you get any pushback?
所有人都认为我疯了
Everyone thought I was crazy.
因此 肯定有人反对
So definitely there were people that resisted it.
有趣的是 有一种非常简单的方法可以克服这种抵制
And it's interesting because there was a really simple way of overcoming that resistance,
首先 创造出所谓的“冠军”
which is first creating what I call champions.
你要教会一小群人
You want to teach people, a small group,
如何以非常安全的方式工作
how to work in a way that is very safe
让他们经历一些考验
and then you want to give them some exposure
然后你就能给出一些可信的指标
and then you want to use a set of metrics where you're able to say,
你就能说 看 我们用服务中断的时间来说事
look, let's just measure how many minutes of outage there is,
我的团队经过了这种培训 这样操作之后停机时间是多少分钟
how many minutes of downtime my team has that has this training and operates this way.
用这个指标和 比方说 你的团队比较
Versus, I don't know, your team,
而你的团队没有经过这种训练
who does not have that
并且似乎认为这种培训和练习没有价值 或者不重要
and who seems to think that doing this type of training and exercises isn't valuable or isn't important.
你一旦这么做之后
And once you do that kind of thing,
所谓的“显著事件”总有一天会发生
you basically end up with what I call a compelling event.
经常会有断电之类的事
So, often there'll be an outage or some other thing
让组织突然意识到
where the organization suddenly and starkly realizes,
哦 我的天哪 我们不能再像以前那样做事了
oh my goodness, we can't keep doing things the way that we've been doing them before.
这就是说服怀疑论者的方法
And that becomes the method you use to overcome the skeptics.
你一方面展示数据和性能数据
You use a combination of data and performance information on the one hand,
再结合指标 讲故事
coupled with metrics, and then great storytelling,
然后等待一个“大的” 或者说严重故障发生
and then you wait for the big one or the scary incident that happens
然后 你就可以说
and you say, you know,
如果我们要在 web 规模或者互联网规模上运维
the whole organization needs this ability
整个组织都需要这种应变能力
if we're going to operate at web scale or internet scale.
*发出赞同的声音*
Mm-hmm (affirmative).
所以我喜欢这个活动的原因是 它不只是停留在亚马逊内部
So what I love about this is that it didn't just stay within Amazon.
相反 它在传播 很多其他公司也在这么做
It spread. A lot of other companies are doing it.
很多人最终接受了“为故障做好准备”的相关知识和工作方式
A lot of people have ended up embracing this knowledge and this process
to, you know, to be prepared.
那下一步是要做什么？
What is next?
我们如何将从 “游戏日” 中学到的知识
How do we continue carrying on the knowledge from Game Day
继续运用到未来的项目和公司中？
into future projects and future companies?
我喜欢把它称为趋同进化
I like to talk about it as convergent evolution.
每个在 web 上运行的大型组织
So every large organization that operates on the web
现在都采用了我提倡的事件管理基础的一个版本
has now adopted a version of both the incident management foundation
that I certainly advocated for
并创立了他们自己的 “游戏日” 测试
and has created their own Game Day testing.
比如 Netflix 将其称为 “混沌猴子”
You know, Netflix calls it the Chaos Monkey.
谷歌也有他们的 Dirt 计划
And Google has their Dirt program.
那么你对未来的 “游戏日” 有什么寄望呢？
So what are your hopes and dreams for Game Day in the future?
首先 让我高兴的是
What I am excited about first of all
我们可以看到人们思维方式的转变
is that we are seeing this evolution now
他们抛弃了系统之间彼此孤立的狭隘观点
from a thinking of silos and thinking of systems as being disconnected to.
转而认为系统之间互相连接 依存于彼此
Systems being fundamentally interconnected, interdependent
而这些系统都是由世界各地的聪明人创造和维护的
and built and run by smart people around the world
是由他们创造的 宏伟的大型工程
that are trying to do great and big things.
几年前 当我刚参加工作时 对运维工作毫不关心
Years ago when I got my start, caring about operations was a backwater.
我觉得那非常无趣
It was not an interesting place.
然后 突然地 我们发现自己能够传播这样一种理念
And suddenly we found ourselves being able to propagate the idea
开发人员和运营人员应当团结协作
that developers and operations people working together
因为这是在万物互联的世界中 创造并应用有用的技术的唯一方式
are the only way that meaningful technology gets built and run in a connected world.
所以 我对未来的希望是
And so my hope for the future is
首先 看到越来越多的人接受这些想法 并学习它们
number one, we're seeing more and more people embracing these ideas
and learning about them.
了解当你建造了人们依赖的东西时
Understanding that when you build something that people depend on,
你有义务确保
you have an obligation to make sure
它是可信赖的、可用的、可靠的
that it's reliable, it's usable, it's dependable,
它是人们可以作为日常生活的一部分来使用的东西
it's something that people can use as part of their daily lives.
而且我们也看到了一种新的学科的诞生
But also we're seeing a new discipline emerge.
人们在对它展开研究
It's being studied, you know,
也有博士正基于这个撰写博士学位论文
there's PhD theses being written on it.
有人为它不断添砖加瓦
It's being built out constantly.
That's awesome.
这真是太棒了
也有人写这方面的书
There's books being written,
That's awesome.
这真是太棒了
也有人写这方面的书
There's books being written,
这个课题极受关注
there's all these new resources that aren't, you know,
远不是少数人在会议上夸夸其谈“理想世界”的状况
just a couple of people talking at a conference about how they think the world should work.
所以我的冀望是
And so my sort of inspirational hope is
首先 你要明白 如果你正在创造软件和技术
one, understand that if you're building software and technology that people use,
那你就会成为社会基础设施的一部分
you're really becoming part of the civic infrastructure.
所以作为一名消防员 我所努力贡献的一系列技能
And so the set of skills that I've tried to contribute as a firefighter
以及现如今涌现的、将这门学科进一步发展的诸多技能和技术
to technology and the skills that are now emerging that are taking that so much farther
它们会成为建造人们日常生活所依赖的东西的基础的一部分
are part of the foundation for building things that people depend on everyday.
很好 这个结尾真不错
Very nice. Oh, that's a great way to end.
Jesse 谢谢你抽出时间来
Thank you so much Jesse for your time.
谢谢
Yeah, thank you.
在 Jesse 看来 像 “游戏日” 或者 “混沌猴子” 这样的演习
In Jesse's vision, exercises like Game Day or Chaos Monkey
不仅是我们不断发展的科技文化的重要组成部分
are a crucial part of our tech culture growing up,
它们对于整个社会也至关重要
but they are also crucial for society at large.
我很喜欢他对此的重视 因为他是对的
And I love that he's putting the stakes that high because he's right.
我们的世界与我们的造物息息相关
Our world depends on the work we do.
早在 90 年代 当电话网络开始崩溃时
That much was obvious back in the 90s
这一点就很明显了
when telephone networks started crashing.
我们认知中的现代生活几乎陷于停顿
Modern life as we know it almost ground to a halt.
责任随创造而来
And there's a duty that goes along with that.
我们有责任关心安全和可靠性
A duty to care about security and reliability,
关心我们造物的应变能力
about the resilience of the things we build.
当然 当谈到在 DevOps 中集成安全工作时
Of course, when it comes to building security into DevOps,
我们才刚刚开始
we're just getting started.
安全 作为一个产业 还在刚刚起步的阶段
Security is one of those... it's so in its infancy, as an industry.
这是 Josh Bressers
That's Josh Bressers.
他是数据搜索软件公司 Elastic 的产品安全主管
He's the head of product security
at a data search software startup called Elastic.
对 Josh 来说 尽管计算机行业已经成长了半个世纪左右
For Josh, even though the computer industry's been maturing for a half-century or so,
我们在这里讨论的安全问题
the kind of security we've been talking about here
却让人觉得它是刚刚才出现的
feels like it just came into its own.
实际上 我会说 作为一个专业
Practically speaking, as what I would say maybe a profession,
安全仍然是非常新的东西 有很多事情我们还不是很了解
security is still very new and there's a lot of things we don't understand.
但我们确实明白
Here's what we do understand though,
在 DevSecOps 的世界中
in a DevSecOps world,
有许多大好机会 可以供人畅想安全工作的可能性
there are some pretty sweet opportunities to get creative about what security can achieve.
我最近和一些人讨论了一个概念
I was recently talking to somebody
他们通过观察用户行为
about a concept where they're using user behavior
来决定用户是否应该能够访问系统
to decide if a user should be able to access the system.
每个人都有特定的行为方式
Everybody has certain behaviors,
比如他们来自哪里
be it where they're coming from,
他们访问系统的时间
time of day they're accessing a system,
他们打字的方式
the way they type,
他们移动鼠标的方式
the way they move their mouse.
我认为他们很有潜力
And so they're actually one of those places that I think
如果做法得当 这种思路可以极为有效
could have some very powerful results if we can do it right,
也就是“注意用户在做什么”的这种思路
where we can pay attention to what someone's doing.
比方说 我表现得很奇怪
And then let's say I'm acting weird
因为我刚刚扭伤了手臂
and you know, I'm weird because I just sprained my wrist.
但系统的另一端并不知情
But you know, the other end doesn't know that.
因此 它可能会说 这种行为就有些奇怪
And so it might say, all right, something's weird,
它就会说 希望你使用双因子认证登录
we want you to log in with your two-factor auth
并且还会给你发条短信之类的
and we're going to also send you a text message or something.
对吧？这就不只是用户名和密码了 它变成了更有趣的东西
Right? And so we've just gone from essentially username and password to something more interesting.
所以我认为 用新的和独特的方式来看待这些问题将是关键
And so I think looking at a lot of these problems in new and unique ways is really going to be key.
在很多情况下 我们只是还没想到
And in many instances, we're just not there yet.
实现这一目标需要我们所描述的两大步骤
Getting there requires those two big steps we've been describing.
第一步 就是自动化 这很重要 因为…
Step one, it's that automation, so crucial because ...
人类很不擅长重复地做同一件事
Humans are terrible at doing the same thing over and over again.
说得对 然后 我们有了第二步 就是文化
Fair. And then we've got step two, the culture,
我们所有人都该对安全性和可靠性负起责任
all of us having a stake in security and reliability,
无论我们的职称是什么
no matter what our job title might say.
当大多数人想到安全团队时
When most people think of the security team,
他们不会认为那是一群快乐的好好先生 对吧?
they don't think of happy nice people, right?
一般印象中 这些人都很可怕 脾气暴躁 令人讨厌
It's generally speaking terrible, grumpy, annoying people,
如果他们出现了 就会毁了你的一天
who if they show up, they're going to ruin your day.
没有人想要这样 对吧?
And nobody wants that, right?
但我认为我们可以克服这种偏见 我们也必须克服它
But I think we can get over that bias because we have to,
你得这么想 - 每天都有更多的安全威胁发生
think of it this way - more security threats happen every day
而且 IT 基础设施每天都在变得规模更大、功能更强
and every day IT infrastructure is growing larger and more powerful.
把这两个事实放在一起
Put those two truths together
如果安全受到轻视 其后果将是灾难性的
and you better live in a world where security gets embraced.
我们需要一个非常 DevSecOps 的世界
A very DevSecOps world
在这个世界里 开发人员和运营人员都在提升系统的安全性
where developers and operations are upping their security games,
提高它们的可靠性
upping their reliability games.
我所谈论的未来是
What I'm talking about is a future
一个自动化被整合到开发和运维的每个阶段的未来
where automation is integrated into every stage
一个所有人都更具全局意识的未来
and everybody's attitudes toward these issues become more holistic.
这就是我们确保未来系统安全的方法
That's how we're going to keep tomorrow's systems safe.
这是我们确保电话能拨通
That's how we're going to keep the phones ringing,
电灯能点亮
the lights on,
让现代生活的方方面面都健康、可靠的方法
all of modern life healthy and strong.
如果你查阅《福布斯》全球前 2000 公司的名单
If you pull up Forbes’ list of the global 2000 organizations,
也就是排名最靠前的 2000 家上市公司
that's the top 2000 public companies,
你会发现其中整整四分之一的公司都采用了 DevOps
it turns out a full quarter of them have embraced DevOps.
集成式敏捷开发正在成为主流的工作方式
Integrated agile workplaces are becoming the rule of the land.
“集成敏捷”（Integrated Agile）是敏捷开发的一个变体
这一变体试图通过在敏捷开发和传统的瀑布开发之间寻找平衡 来克服两者的缺点
用不了几年 DevSecOps 的思考方式
And in a few years thinking in terms of DevSecOps
可能会成为技术从业者的第二天性
might become second nature.
我们希望尽可能快
We want to go as fast as possible,
但想在长距离比赛中提高速度
but the long game is actually faster
正需要团队中的所有成员都同心协力
when every part of the team is in the race together.
下一集 我们将面临数据的大爆炸
Next episode, we're getting hit by the data explosion.
人类已经进入了“泽字节”时代
Humans have entered the Zettabyte era.
泽字节 = Zettabyte = ZB 是用于表示数据量的单位
1ZB 为 1*10^9 TB
到 2020 年 我们将在服务器上存储大约 40 泽字节的数据
By 2020, we'll be storing about 40 zettabytes of information
而这些服务器大部分甚至现在还不存在
on servers that mostly don't even exist yet.
原播客发布于 2018 年
但是我们该如何让这些数据有用呢？
But how are we supposed to make all that data useful?
我们如何使用高性能计算和开源项目
How do we use high-performance computing and open source projects
让数据为我们所用呢
to get our data working for us?
我们会在《代码英雄》第二季第 6 集中找到答案
We find out in episode 6 of Command Line Heroes.
提醒一下
And a reminder,
我们整季都在致力于《代码英雄》游戏的开发
all season long we're working on Command Line Heroes: The Game.
这是我们自己的开源项目
It's our very own open source project
我们很高兴能见证它的诞生
and we've loved watching it all come together,
但是我们需要你来帮助我们完成
but we need you to help us finish.
如果你点击 redhat.com/commandlineheroes
If you hit up redhat.com/commandlineheroes,
你就能看到该如何贡献
you can discover how to contribute.
也可以深入了解我们在这期节目中讨论过的任何内容
And you can also dive deeper into anything we've talked about in this episode.
《代码英雄》是红帽原创播客
Command Line Heroes is an original podcast from Red Hat.
你可以在 Apple Podcast、Google Podcast
Listen for free on Apple Podcasts, Google Podcasts,
或是其他你喜欢的途径免费收听
or wherever you do your thing.
我是 Saron Yitbarek
I'm Saron Yitbarek.
坚持编程 下期再见
Until next time, keep on coding.